[Music]
hi everyone this is Ravi welcome to
tricentis tasa Advanced
Training as you all know I have already
published 48 YouTube videos covering
beginners intermediate and advanced
level
Concepts from few days onwards I've
started posting YouTube videos covering
realtime
scenarios where you might encounter
different types of obstacles and how can
we solve those obstacles while
automating your test cases so I already
published six different
obstacles that we encounter while
automating your test
cases this is our
lesson
49 in terms of overall trient TOS
automation training and this is our
lesson 7 or abstra 7 in terms of
realtime
scenarios in this lesson I'm going to
teach you a realtime
scenario where you need to interact with
the controls like autoc complete text
box and also you need to count the
number of values that displays in
autocomplete text box what do you mean
by that so autocomplete text box is
nothing but it's a kind of drop- down
but you need to enter a value in the
text box based on the entered value it
display the drop-down values in your
autocomplete text box it is kind of drop
down but the drop- down values depends
on the text that you enter in the text
box so now let us see what is the
obstacle that we are going to solve for
this is our seventh obstacle which is
categorized as hard and the obstacle
name is and Counting okay let's go for
it
and
here autoc complete text
box type the given characters in the box
then count the entries and enter the
number in the text box so what do you
mean by that so here this is your text
copy this text and you need to type the
text that is displaying here a a a and
as soon as you type a AA it displays
three different drop-down values based
on the input that you
provided and then you need to count the
number of drop- down values and enter
the count
here as three so good job so let me try
again see now it has a value of
CCC if I enter c c c now you have the
value of two the count of drop- down
values are two so in this case you need
to enter two then your automation
problem is solved so now to automate
this scenario let us go to trient tasa
so this is my
tasa I would like to capture the objects
from the application that I would like
to automate for that right click on this
obstacles folder select scan and click
on
application so this is my application
select the application click on scan
so before I scan I would like to close
this we forgot to do one thing okay let
me close the xcan here what I'm going to
do I'm going to just type some value
here okay I'm going to type let's say
BBB so that I can capture one of the
element from this drop down list also
okay so let's go back here now right
click and scan the
application so this is my application
select the application click on
scan now let
us make the window little bigger so that
you can understand what I'm doing okay
so here we need to concentrate on couple
of things while scanning your objects
okay so first of
all let us bring these
filters expand the filter by clicking
towards the right side okay so here if
you scroll down so this is the text that
we need to capture right e e e so this
is the container that I would like to
capture check this
container and then highlight this
container okay I highlight the object
see this is the text I need okay but if
you see
here I don't want to take the inner text
property here because this keeps
changing if I refresh the page sometimes
it displays e e e sometimes it displays
BBB right so that means this is dynamic
so that's why I don't want inner text
I'm removing the inner text from the
object okay I'm going to keep ID and the
tag so that is done now let's select
autoc complete object as well what is
this autocomplete basically it's a text
box okay and
then I would like to
capture the text where I'm going to
enter the number of values that is
displaying in the drop down correct so
now not number it's a count of drop-
down values so for that let's capture
that object as well let's come down here
so this is the one get the entry count
and enter here this is my text box
select this one and now we need to
capture these elements right for that
let's scroll down here if you see here I
have a UL object and Li object what is
UL object let's select
this and then let's highlight this so so
this
entire container or this entire section
is UL object and also I need one of the
element from here one of the LI element
right let's highlight this Li I've
selected the first one it's going to
highlight the first one see the first
one I don't want to capture each and
every element okay but here I would like
to make a small modification for the LI
element
what is the modification I don't want to
have ID as a property because I want to
count the number of drop- down values
right so this ID is unique for each
drop- down value so I'm going to remove
that unique
identification now this is not uniquely
identified not identified because the
tag is Li so that is okay because I
would like to capture how many number of
Li tags are here right so now let's go
to the top now rename this
module as obstacle name copy
this and paste it
here and one thing we need to take care
here is we need to Reg regular
expression we need to use regular
expression for the title I don't want to
use entire page title inad I would like
to use hasri as a regular expression
okay so what we did here see Let Me
Explain one more time I've captured the
container div container of this
text right but for that div container
I've removed the inner text property
because this keeps on changing and then
I have captured the autocomplete text
box and then I've also captured this
text box where I enter the count of
values right and then I've captured the
UI and Li
elements and for Li element I've removed
the ID property because each drop- down
value will have their own will have
their unique IDs so I don't want to
include that unique ID now save this
module and then close this so now let's
go back to your module here so this is
the new module that we
capture double click on this so this is
the new module now let us create a new
test case right click on obstacle
folder create test case
name this with the same obstacle
name double click on test case now let
us automate the test case to automate
you can simply drag this module and drop
here so let us see what is The Logical
order that we perform the actions first
capture the inner text of
this and then enter value into autoc
complete and then
we need to calculate the number of
values before you enter the count here
that's why I need to bring this
here right and then you enter calculate
the number of drop down values and enter
the count in the text box so now this
makes sense so now let us automate
this here I need to rename let me rename
this one as as
text because this text keeps on changing
right now I need to store the inner text
of this container into buffer for that
select action mode as buffer and here
now you
select this drop down and select inner
text and I would like to store that in
buffer called text done now you need to
enter the value that you stored in the
buffer in this auto complete so for that
here I cannot simply type the text or I
cannot simply type the text here right
to enter the value in the autocomplete
because this is autoc complete text it's
not simple text box so we need to use a
send Keys option
here Square braces
send let me do one thing
okay open Square braces send
keys and then what keys I would like to
send I would like to send the value that
I'm storing in buffer for that open
curly braces capital B to call the
buffer and open Square braces this is my
buffer
close Square braces close curly braces
right and then close curly braces for
send
keys right I'm sending a keys with a
text that I'm storing in buffer and now
coming to Li here once I enter any value
here now it is time to calculate the
number of Li objects right for that I'm
going to use the method called result
code what I'm going to do I'm going to
store into a
buffer what I'm going to store into
buffer the result count
here enter result count method and I
would like to store that into a buffer
called
count right so this is going to give me
the number of
Li
containers available in the dropdown
result count I'm storing that into
buffer called count now you need to
enter the count whatever you received or
whatever you store in the
buffer where you need to enter in the
text box here I'm going to call the
buffer count
open curly braces capital
B open Square
braces count close Square braces close
curly
braces and your action mode is
input so let me explain again I'm
storing the inner text of this element
see whenever I refresh right it's keep
changing right whatever I get I'm going
to store that into a buff buffer called
text by using inner text and
then I am sending a
keys with the value that I'm storing in
the buffer
text and then once you send the
keys you will get the number of drop
down values which are Li com Li objects
now I'm counting those Li objects by
using result count and I'm storing that
result count into a buffer called
count this gives me the count of drop
down values and then I'm entering the
same
count by using the buffer I
stored into the text box here so now
before I execute the test case let's
refresh this
page now let's change change the work
state as
complete now save the test case right
click and run the test case in
scratchbook see it got the inner text it
typed the inner text called a AA how
many drop down values it displayed three
the same count it entered in the text
box Let me refresh this and execute one
more time now this time DDD right
right click and run in
scratchbook now here it captured DDD it
entered DDD how many drop down values it
displayed 1 2 3 4 5 the same number it
entered here as well so let's see the
test results if you see the test results
here
expand this first it is storing the
value into a buffer call text and then
the same thing is entered in
autocomplete box and then the result
count of Li objects stored see under
buffer called count how much five the
same thing is entered into a text box so
the test case is pass so that means we
solved our automation challenge so if
you have any queries leave your queries
in the comment box I'll try to respond
to your
queries hope you all understand how can
we solve an obstacle where you need to
interact with the controls like auto
complete text box and you need to
calculate the number of drop- down
values that are displaying in the
autocomplete text box and you need to
enter the count into the text next
box please do subscribe to the channel
click on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos don't forget to like and share
the video thank you
[Music]